Finding Aid for the Lester Breslow Papers LSC.2246
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Research and scholarship, 1932-2008
  - Subseries 2.4: Conference presentations and talks, 1955-2007 (Box 84, Folder 7-18, Box 85, Box 86, Box 87, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94, Box 95, Box 96, Folder 1-5)
    This subseries has been organized in chronological order.
- Series 3: Non-university work, 1950-2009
  This series covers Breslow's work that was not related to his teaching position at UCLA. This includes committees he sat on, consulting work, legislation he worked on, and testimonies he provided for court cases. Topics include tobacco, Los Angeles County health services, the Little Hoover Commission, reports for the California legislature, and health care costs.
  - Subseries 3.1: Committees and consulting, 1971-2009
    This subseries consists of materials related to Breslow's participation in local, state, and national committees and commissions, as well as consulting services he provided. His involvement varied from chair to reviewer, and prominent committees he served on include the Asbestiform Fibers Committee, the Armed Forces Epidemiological Board, the Governor's Committee on Health Care Costs, the Institute of Medicine, National Cancer Institute, and the President's Commission on the Health Needs of the Nation.
    - Asbestiform fibers committee, 1982-1983 (Box 96, Folder 6-7, Box 97, Folder 1-4)
    - American Cancer Society California Division Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - American Heart Association, 1975-1985 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Armed forces epidemiological board, 1978-1979 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Blue Cross Association, 1978-1982 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - California Wellness Foundation, 1996-1999 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Citizens for the treatment of high blood pressure, 1973-1978 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Center for Health Improvement, 2000-2008 (Box 98, Folder 5-7, Box 99, Folder 1-6)
    - Cleveland Hospital Association, 1993 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Efficacy and safety advisory panel, circa 1980 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Governor's committee on health care costs, 1978-1979 (Box 100, Folder 1-2)
    - Health Care Policy Advisory Board, 2000 (Box 100, Folder 3-4)
    - Health systems management, 1975-1982 (Box 100, Folder 5-6)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1976-1986 (Box 100, Folder 7-9, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Folder 1-5)
    - King/Drew Medical Center, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles County health services and public health, 1972-2009 (Box 103, Folder 7-8, Box 104, Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108, Folder 1-2)
    - Little Hoover Commission, 1987-2004 (Box 108, Folder 3-4)
    - Maryland state-wide health network, 2000-2001 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - National Cancer Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 108, Folder 6-12)
    - Oregon state, 1995-1998 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Partnership for prevention, 1993-1994 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, 1995 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - President's commission, 1943-1952 (Box 109, Folder 4-8, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114, Box 115, Box 116, Box 117, Box 118, Box 119, Box 120, Box 121, Box 122, Box 123, Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Senior risk reduction program, 1971-2003 (Box 124, Folder 2-8, Box 125, Box 126, Folder 1-4)
    - Tobacco control, 1981-2006 (Box 126, Folder 5-6, Box 127, Box 128, Box 129, Folder 1-4)
    - U.S. National Committee on Vital and Health Statistics, 1976-1980 (Box 129, Folder 5-10, Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3.2: Legislation and testimonies, 1950-2003
    This subseries contains materials related to court cases Breslow testified for or legislation he supported. Materials include correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, and other documents regarding state and national legislation. Topics include health care costs at the state level, the Child Health Assurance Act, health care workers, public health recodification, and support and funding for health services and research.
    - Annotations of California legislature report, 1950 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Association of Schools of Public Health, 1978-1979 (Box 130, Folder 3-6, Box 131, Folder 1-4)
    - California Assembly on health care costs, 1978 (Box 131, Folder 5-6, Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Child health assurance act, 1978 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Cranston presidential campaign, 1983 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Health manpower, 1978 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Health services and research, 1977-1982 (Box 132, Folder 5-8, Box 133, Box 134, Folder 1-2)
    - Public health recodification, 1984 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Senate subcommittee on health and scientific research, 1977-1978 (Box 134, Folder 4-5)
    - Superior Court of California, 2003-2003 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Senate, 1985 June 14 (Box 134, Folder 7-8)